MARTA CARLOS

@ m.carlos@campus.fct.unl.pt

**** +351 917 316 052

github.com/mbbcarlos

in linkedin.com/in/marta-carlos-244390162/

Rua do Rato, Bairro do Soutelo nº44, 2845-257 Seixal, Portugal



EDUCATION

Integrated Masters in Computer Science

Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa

2015 - September 2021

♀ Lisbon, Portugal

Currently finishing my Masters Dissertation about the use of real and/or historic data regarding fighting forest wildfires in Virtual Reality. To achieve the resulting prototype, I developed a three-layer solution, involving Flask, Kotlin, Docker and Unreal Engine 4. This prototype was also tested by real future users.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance

Departamento de Ciências Sociais e Aplicadas, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa

m December 2020 - Present

Collaborated on the front-end development of a website, built with React and Node.js, for photo management and visualization.

Teaching Assistant - Introdução à Programação B Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologias, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa

Ctober 2019 - January 2019

During the first semester, I taught one laboratory class for the course unit "Introdução à Programação B" where I focused on making coding less intimidating for students and held office hours to help answer the students' questions.

Research Project

Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa

February 2018 - July 2018

Member of the research project titled "Realidade Virtual em cenários de Incêndios Florestais", where I researched and summarized a methodology regarding the use of GIS data in Unreal Engine 4.

EXTRACURRICULAR

Vice-President of Núcleo de Informática FCT NOVA Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologias, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa

march 2019 - June 2019

Within the last four months of my time as Treasurer, I also took the role of Vice-President. In this year, we improved on the club's main event (Hackathon FCT NOVA) by changing it to a bigger location, changing the 24 hours period to 48 hours and worked with sponsors to provide relevant workshops the week before the event. During this time, my team spirit and sense of responsibility were re-enforced even more and I was able to strengthen my interpersonal skills, as well as truly understand what good time management meant.

Treasurer do Núcleo de Informática FCT NOVA Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologias, Universidade NOVA de Lisboa

₩ June 2018 - June 2019

During this time, I had the amazing opportunity to talk with technology companies and collaborate directly with them for events such workshops and a Hackathon. Additionally, I held all the financial responsibility of the student group, such as bookkeepping, payments for merchandise, food and other event related payments.

PROFILE

I consider myself a very organized and determined person who goes after what I believe in. I was an active member of the student club Núcleo de Informática FCT for three years, where I developed and improved both my technical and soft skills via working as a team to plan and lead student workshops and hackathons.

I have a special interest in computer graphics and the development of web applications, including Front-End and Full Stack. Another area of programming that I am curious in learning more about is game development, given the creative possibilities it can entail.

My hobbies of drawing, photography and video editing brought me to computer science since these hobbies awoke my interest in the technology behind software like Adobe After Effects and Adobe Photoshop.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java Pytho	n Javascript Kotlin
React Boot	strap Flutter Typescript
QGIS Unre	al Engine 4 PowerPoint
GDAL Git Adobe Photos	LaTeX Adobe Premiere hop Adobe Illustrator

PERSONAL SKILLS

Linguistic

• Portuguese: Mother Tongue

• English: level C1

• Spanish: level A2

Driver's License B